Inventory of the Education Subject Collection, 1896-1998
Hoover Institution Archives
Education Subject Collection,
1896-2009
XX763
51 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 videotape cassette (21.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, newsletters, serial issues, and other printed matter, relating to various aspects of education in the United States and abroad.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Education.; Education--United States.; United States.; Video tapes.
Container List
Please check card catalog for increments that may have been received after April 1996.
- Advisory Committee on Private Enterprise in Foreign Aid (Box 1)
- Afghanistan (Box 19)
- African-American Institute (Box 1)
- Agricultural Development Council
- American Association of Christian Schools
- American Association of School Administrators
- American Association of University Women (Hawaii) (Box 19)
- American Council on Education. Report, 1983 (Box 12)
- American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research (Box 1)
- American Federation of Teachers
- Americans for the Universality of UNESCO. Newsletter, March 1985 (Box 12)
- Annual Insider (Box 1)
- Association of American Publishers. Report on cost analysis for instructional materials, by the California Committee of Regional Managers
- Atlantic Community News
- Atlantic Organizations. Directory
- Auckland Teachers College Council (Box 19)
- Bay Area Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 2)
- British Institute of Human Rights
- California Assessment Program
- California Monitor of Education
- California Legal Foundation
- Carnegie Corporation of New York
- Catholic League
- Center for Peace Studies (Box 3)
- Christian School Communicator
- Chronicle of Higher Education
- Chronicles of Culture
- College Management
- Colloquy (World Affairs Council)
- Committee on the Present Danger
- Common Focus
- Communicator (National Association of Elementary School Principals)
- COPRED Peace Chronicle (Consortium on Peace Research, Education, and Development)
- Council of Europe (Box 19)
  - Teachers' Seminar "Schooling of Gypsies and Travellers' Children," 1987
  - Council for Cultural Co-operation Project No. 8 "Innovation in Primary Education." Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 20)
- Creative Initative (Box 3)
- Early childhood education. Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 11)
- Education (Box 4)
- Education. Printed matter, 1942-1984, relating to education in the U.S. and in other countries. In English, Spanish and Ethiopic (Box 11)
- Education - United States - History. Naber, G. M., "Midwinter Letter to the Teachers of Whiteley County, Indiana," 1896 (Box 21)
- Education Commission of the States (Box 4)
- Education Finance Center
- Education Voucher Institute
- Educational Excellence Network
  - Newsletters, 1985-1986 (some gaps) (Box 12, 16-17)
  - Reports, 1986-1987 (some gaps) (Box 19)
- Educational planning. Reports, 1959, 1963, 1964. In French and Spanish. See also International Institute for Educational Planning (Box 16)
- Educational Testing Service. See National Assessment of Educational Progress
- European Culural Foundation (Box 19)
- Finland
- Finn, Chester E., Jr.
- Ford Foundation (Box 4)
- Foreign Affairs Research
- Fort Mason Center, San Francisco
- Foundation for Teaching Economics
- Foundation for Youth Development
- Friends Committee on National Legislation
- General Motors Corporation. Reports relating to education program, 1984 (Box 11)
- Global Perspectives in Education, Inc. (Box 8)
- Great Plains Legal Foundation (Box 4)
- Great Plains National
- Haavelsrud, Magnus
- Hawaii. See American Association of University Women (Hawaii)
- Heritage Foundation (Box 5)
- Hoover Institution - Central and Western European Collections, 1981
- Husen, Torsten (Box 20)
- IBM World Trade Corporation, African Education Centre, Nigeria (Box 5)
- Institute for Educational Affairs
- Institute for Educational Leadership, Inc. (Box 9, 12)
- Institute of International Education. Reports and studies, 1983 (Box 12)
- Institute for Liberty and Community (Box 19)
- International Education Project (Box 5)
- International Institute for Educational Planning (Box 21)
- International Peace Research (Box 5)
- Innovator (University of Michigan)
- Iran. Mehregan: An Iranian Journal of Culture and Politics, 1992 (Box 21)
- Japan (Box 5)
- Kappa Delta Pi. Publications
- Lakeland High School (Shrub Oak, New York) (Box 19)
- Leadership
- Learning: Magazine for Creative Writing (Box 6)
- Ligue internationale contre le racisme et l'antisemitisme
- Maher, Robert E. (Box 19)
- Mexico. Publications relating to education and to social and economic conditions. In Spanish (Box 10)
- Michael Glazier, Inc. (Box 6)
- Minority Rights Group
- Moral instruction in California schools (Box 17)
- Moral Majority Report (Box 6)
- Multiculturalism. Videotape cassette, 1993, relating to the issue of multiculturalism on American university campuses (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
- National Academy of Education. Report and working papers of the Committee on Anthropology and Education, 1978 (Box 20)
- National Assessment of Educational Progress, Educational Testing Service (Box 18-19)
- National Christian Action Coalition (Box 6)
- National Coalition for Equality in Learning. Report by Ward J. Ghory, September 1993 (Box 21)
- National Coalition on Television Violence (Box 6)
- National Commission on Excellence in Educational Administration (Box 17)
- National Committee for Citizens in Education (Box 6)
- National Committee on United States-China Relations. Publications, 1978-1982 (Box 16)
- National Education Association (Box 6)
- National Voter
- NATO Review
- Netherlands (Box 10)
- Northeast Asia-U.S. Forum (Box 6)
- OECD Observer
- Pacific News Service
- Peace and Change
- Peace Corps (Box 7)
- Phi Delta Kappa
- Philippines (Box 12, 16)
  - Printed matter, 1983-1984
  - Proceedings of workshop/seminars, University of the Philippines, 1977-1978, 1980
- Physics education (Box 7)
- Policy Review
- Principal
- Profiles of Philippine Universities and Colleges
- Project Interface
- Rand Graduate Institute
- Reading Reform Foundation (Box 17)
- Regional Institute of Higher Education and Development (Box 10)
- Rockford Institute (Box 7)
- School Administrator
- School and innovation
- Science
- Shenfield, Arthur, From Campus to Capitol (Box 4)
- South and Southeast Asia Studies, University of California, Berkeley (Box 7)
- Soviet Union (Box 19)
- Spotlight (Box 7)
- Stanford Libraries Associates
- Stanford University News Service
- Study of High Schools
- Sweden. See Husen, Torsten
- Sysorex Information Systems, Inc. Proposal entitled "U.S.A.I.D. Learning Technologies Project," n.d. (Box 12)
- Taiwan. Ministry of Education. Printed matter, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
- Taxpayers Education Lobby (Box 8)
- Teacher education. Imig, David G., "American Teacher Education at a Crossroads: Five Trends in Search of a Solution," 1995 (Box 21)
- Teacher Education Reports (Box 8)
- Teacher testing and educational testing. Printed material, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
- Teachers College Record on the Possibility of Newness (Box 8)
- Thailand (Box 12)
- Unesco (Box 8, 10-11, 13-15)
- Unicef (Box 8)
- United States - National security (Box 6)
- United States. Congress. House. Committee on Appropriations (Box 3)
- United States. Congress. Senate. Labor and Human Resources Subcommittee on Education and Employment (Box 7)
- United States. Department of Commerce (Box 3)
- United States. Department of Education (Box 3, 17)
- Van Geel, Tyll: "Parental Preferences and the Politics of Spending Public Educational Funds" (Box 6)
- War on Want (Box 8)
- Washington Office on Latin America
- World Bank. Includes cassettes and film strips (Box 9, 20)
- World politics in the 1980s (Box 8)
- World Research, Inc.
- Incremental Materials (Box 22-52)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described.